

AFTON GAUNTLETT

Web Developer

Chantilly, VA 20152

aftongauntlett@gmail.com

804-909-4118

I have over 15 years of professional data entry and research experience. I am currently studying web development and my goal is to become a front-end web developer. I have a strong ambition for creating creative websites.

Willing to relocate to: Research Triangle Park, NC - Asheville, NC - Boulder, CO

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Online Store Owner

Baysil Creations - Chantilly, VA October 2009 to Present

Business owner for retail arbitrage, artwork and custom designs.

Laboratory Technician

ATCC - Manassas, VA March 2019 to March 2020

Operate equipment, record data on controlled documents and enter sensitive information into proprietary ERP system. Ability to manage time and schedule with limited supervision. Communicate effectively with team members, supervisors and other departments on production order status. Follow production orders to complete operations in a timely manner. Experience working under cGMPs and ISO 9000:2001 specifications. Understand and demonstrate proper lab safety protocols and PPE. Read, adhere and document training for all SOP's and WI's required for position. Cross departmental training when required. Participate in interviews and training of new employees.

Office Automation Clerk

Travelers Insurance - Chantilly, VA July 2018 to November 2018

Short term contract - Assist with OPUS filing and compliance duties. Make copies, fax, and print important documents. Responsible for gathering files from other departments and retrieving stored files as needed. Prepare inactive files to be shipped to storage.

Research Assistant

Access Confidential - Chantilly, VA November 2017 to June 2018 Maintaining Access Confidential's proprietary database with updated information by researching daily press, advertising trade publications, and other online databases, as well as calling companies directly to confirm or update database information. Conducting email correspondence ("bounce tests") as a supplement to phone calling in order to verify accuracy of email addresses. Conducting extensive internet research by looking at company websites, trade publications, online newspapers and subscription-based resources with the purpose of verifying company information and statistics. - Performing database entry in a proprietary database which involves researching, editing and verifying information for accuracy before entering key data into proper fields, while adhering to established, strict formatting guidelines.

Office Assistant

Macoy Publishing - Henrico, VA, US October 2015 to October 2017

Operate multi-head embroidery machine, engraving machine, hot press machine and other equipment as needed. Package and address orders using UPS World Ship and Stamps.com. Assist with inventory and catalog entry. Assist with merchandise photography for catalogs and website. Assist with data entry using Microsoft Office/Excel and In SQL. Meet daily deadlines and goals.

Data Entry Specialist

Smash Direct - Ashland, VA March 2008 to January 2009

List items efficiently and accurately within deadline; meet monthly quotas; locate items quickly; learn new computer programs and software, research items; photograph and describe items professionally for sale; communicate between departments and occasionally assist customers with questions.

Quality Control Manager

Richmond Camera - Richmond, VA September 2006 to March 2008

Quality control hundreds of orders each day; document/account management; handle a high volume of credit card transactions; package and prepare time sensitive mail; coordinate transactions between multiple departments; contact customers about pending orders; inventory restocking/checking in; sustain and meet deadlines. I also did a variety of other tasks - including color correction/editing of images via computer, scanning and imaging film, using various equipment for making buttons, t-shirts, mugs, etc.

EDUCATION

Career Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

George Washington University - Arlington, VA March 2020 to Present

High school diploma

Hopewell High School - Hopewell, VA 2004

SKILLS

- Inventory (5 years)
- Data Entry (10+ years)
- Quality Control (5 years)
- MS Office (10+ years)
- Research (10+ years)
- Computer Repair (5 years)
- Online Marketing (5 years)
- Troubleshooting (10+ years)
- Laboratory Procedures
- ERP Systems
- Excel
- Word
- Customer Service
- JavaScript
- · CSS
- JQuery
- Bootstrap
- HTML
- Node.js
- Vue.js

LINKS

http://linkedin.com/in/afton-smith-027399152

https://github.com/aftongauntlett

CERTIFICATIONS AND LICENSES

Driver's License

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

I have volunteered for MAGFest, Inc. for over ten years. MAGFest is a non-profit organization dedicated to furthering the appreciation of video games, video game culture, and video game music. There are 20,000+ attendees at the main event held annually with numerous minor events throughout the year. I assist with technical operations and web development.